hi everybody welcome back to the channel
today we're going to look at this ice
cream from cruster and Malika I think
I've said that right
and we're going to recreate ourselves at
home if you want to see how we do it
stick around and we'll show you
[Music]
we went to our local supermarket which
unfortunately happens to be a waitrose
here in the UK and you know there's a
very specific type of person that can
afford to use waitrose supermarkets that
is not us by the way
um walk past the ice cream aisle as I
always do just see if there's anything
new in there although this isn't new I
had never eaten this so I thought we'd
buy some and the other night we sat down
it's like six pound fifty for this
little tub you know what does that
equate to 12 11 something like that 14
Canadian dollars it's it's a lot of
money
we sat down the other night we watched
random film and we started digging into
this and
it was actually really nice there's a
couple of things to note it is
it doesn't freeze hard it's straight out
the freezer and it's surprisingly soft
and that is for one reason only it is 20
sugar so obviously something to remember
this is gelato so gelato is lower fat
and high sugar than American ice cream
or standard ice creams although some
people like to argue gelato just means
ice cream yes it does it's the Italian
word for ice cream but they are very
different products gelato and ice cream
I've done a whole video on the
differences I'll put a link in the
description below check it out it I go
through what the notable differences are
between the two
but when we look down on the ingredients
here it's got glucose syrup it's got no
more sugar in it it's got the
amarina Cherry sauce which is made up of
sugar and glucose syrup itself
there's just sugar coming out of
everywhere like I said it's 20 sugar
content six percent fat so really quite
low in fat probably as low as you can go
fat content
for gelato before it becomes
almost sherbet
it's
quite tasty it is quite tasty you know
we've
munched away through you know most of
the tub something to note now obviously
this is a mascarpone amarena Cherry
gelato so it's a mascarpone base with
the Cherry kind of
swirl
Ripple let's use an old-fashioned term a
cherry Ripple
[Music]
cherry
is very forward
but it's very sweet the Cherry Ripple is
very very sweet
it's kind of it's got a little bit of
iciness to it but that's kind of to be
expected but
very sweet
it's too sweet considering how sweet the
base is
but
we can change that so that's what we're
going to do today we're going to remake
this at home and just adjust some of the
sweetness so that it's a bit more in
tune with what I would like to eat what
my wife would like to eat
if you want to go full sugar if you want
to go full on Captain diabetes then find
these cherries amarina cherries add
shitloads of sugar to it while you're
processing them and then follow the
recipe that way but we're going to use
Morello cherry base no we're going to
use Morello Cherry swirl
let's just get stuck into it shall we
and for this recipe what we did was we
took our Morello Cherry compote this is
straight off the shelf from a
supermarket
um the Morello cherries are a little bit
more sour than the amarina cherries so
it goes really well with the base we're
going to empty the jar into the pan and
start warming it up when we're going to
add in some liquid glucose this will
drop the freezing point and also sweeten
it somewhat but not as much as table
sugar would once that's all nicely
combined and warmed and emulsified
together you're going to take it off the
heat and strain it through a sieve so
that you're left with your liquid
element only you don't want any of the
Cherry flesh left
once it's in a container just put it
aside and we'll use it a bit later on
for the gelato base we're going to start
with the milk as we always do and add in
our sugars along with our milk powder
and a stabilizer now gelato uses a lot
more stabilizer than American ice cream
because of the low fat content and as
you can see here I'm running the
gauntlet with the pan I should have used
a bigger pan but hey we'll try and get
through
once it comes up to the temperature that
your stabilizer needs that is likely
between 60 and 70 degrees Centigrade
you're going to add in your Mascarpone
cheese uh yeah there's not a lot of room
left here one swift far and I'm gonna go
over the edge so you know bear with me I
think we might just make it once it's
all combined we're going to take it off
the heat and pop it in a container and
then stick it in a fridge overnight to
chill down
once the base is completely chilled down
that's probably overnight or you know a
good four or five hours later take it
out the fridge give it a nice quick stir
to loosen it all back up again the
sometimes the mascarpone will settle one
way or another but just mix it all back
together it will all re-emulsify pop it
in your ice cream machine and churn away
there's a lot of sugar in this like I
said so it will take a bit longer in my
machine it took 18 minutes to turn this
batch because it's quite a large batch
once it's ready you can start loading up
your tub by layering in nice spoonfuls
of your cherry sauce and and then follow
that with more of your ice cream base
until your tub is completely full when
you're then going to pop it in the
freezer to completely harden off
[Music]
ice cream is out the freezer just it
kind of goes
hard but I've adjusted the sugar to suit
your freezer might be different you know
20 sugar it's still going to go hard in
a home freezer that's just the way they
are
Morello cherries I'm looking forward to
seeing how these two have combined so
let's dish them up and see what it
tastes like
[Music]
scooped really well scooped just like
gelato does it's kind of
you you need to play the game with the
stabilizers carefully with gelato if you
don't use stabilizers in gelato
you're gonna struggle to keep it in the
freezer for any more than a couple of
days it just won't work it will turn to
ice really quickly the lack of fat
players Havoc with a freezing schedule
so all gelato that you buy in the shops
is stabilized
do it at home if you're doing this
because it will really help
let's try some and see what it tastes
like
so for me personally this is a much more
balanced ice cream it's not as sweet
because you don't have that extreme
sweetness coming from the Cherry sauce
and you go too sweet with things like
that with with fruit sauces or swirls
they start to taste artificial and
that's actually what happened with the
store-bought one it started to taste
like an artificial Cherry sauce they do
state that they use
you know Cherry
um reduction and stuff like that in
there so I'm not exactly sure what's
gone into making that sauce but here you
can control it I've used a store-bought
Morello Cherry compact which is
fine ingredients is pretty simple on
here it's Morello cherries a small
amount of sugar water and then some
starches to thicken it up with a bit of
vanilla extract likely to boost the
flavor but it really complements the the
musk Pony base and that's really
important because you need the add-ins
to complement the base not just a wave
of sugar
like I said in in the video earlier on
you had a 20 sugar content across this
whole base from the store-bought one
and that can be too high for a lot of
people and when you got that
extreme sweetness of the Cherry sauce
coming through it it's a bit off-putting
but again you can control that you can
use different cherries if you want to
add the Cherry flesh into the ice cream
you absolutely can you're free to do
whatever you kind of want to do
I would say If You're Gonna Keep The
Flash in there I'd probably start adding
a little bit of sucrose or table sugar
to the recipe because the glucose
whilst it does help with the freezing
point it will not affect the Cherry
pieces quite as well as sucrose as well
so you might want to play around with
those numbers but nice smooth creamy
mascarpony base with a semi-sweet
semi-tart Cherry sauce going through
definitely worth trying you can support
the channel on Kofi I'll put a link on
screen and down below so head on over
and help us keep this channel going
thanks for much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe and we'll
see you next time
please